<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>8957</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Cotard syndrome, self-awareness, and I-concepts</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Gennaro, Rocco Joseph</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Consciousness</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Cotard syndrome</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Higher-order thoughts</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">I-concepts</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Self-awareness</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Somatoparaphrenia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Thought insertion</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Various psychopathologies of self-awareness, such as somatoparaphrenia and thought insertion in schizophrenia, might seem to threaten the viability of the higher-order thought (HOT) theory of consciousness since it requires a HOT about one’s own mental state to accompany every conscious state. The HOT theory of consciousness says that what makes a mental state a conscious mental state is that there is a HOT to the effect that “I am in mental state M.” I have argued in previous work that a HOT theorist can adequately respond to this concern with respect to somatoparaphrenia and thought insertion. There is also Cotard syndrome which is a rare neuropsychiatric disorder in which people hold the delusional belief that they are dead, do not exist, or have lost their blood or internal organs. In this paper, I argue that HOT theory has nothing to fear from it either and can consistently account for what happens in such unusual cases. I analyze Cotard syndrome in light of my previous discussion of somatoparaphrenia and thought insertion, and argue that HOT theory can provide a somewhat analogous account without the worry of inconsistency. It is crucial to recognize that there are multiple “self-concepts” and levels of HOTs which can help to provide a more nuanced explanation. With regard to the connection between consciousness and self-consciousness, it is proposed that Cotard patients are indeed capable of having some “I-thoughts” about their bodies and mental states.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">MIND Group</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-03-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://philosophymindscience.org/index.php/phimisci/article/view/8957</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.33735/phimisci.2020.I.41</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Philosophy and the Mind Sciences; Vol. 1 No. I (2020): Special Issue: Radical Disruptions of Self-Consciousness; 1-20</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2699-0369</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.33735/phimisci.2020.I</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://philosophymindscience.org/index.php/phimisci/article/view/8957/8535</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2020 Rocco Joseph Gennaro</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>