<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>9185</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Brain structural complexity and consciousness</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Song, Chen</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Consciousness</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Sleep</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Brain structural complexity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Individual differences</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Multimodal brain imaging</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Structure shapes function. Understanding what is structurally special about the brain that allows&amp;nbsp;it to generate consciousness remains a fundamental scientific challenge. Recently, advances in&amp;nbsp;brain imaging techniques have made it possible to measure the structure of human brain, from&amp;nbsp;the morphology of neurons and neuronal connections to the gross anatomy of brain regions,&amp;nbsp;in-vivo and non-invasively. Using advanced brain imaging techniques, it was discovered that the&amp;nbsp;structural diversity between neurons and the topology of neuronal connections, as opposed to the&amp;nbsp;sheer number of neurons or neuronal connections, are key to consciousness. When the structural&amp;nbsp;diversity is high and the connections follow a modular topology, neurons will become functionally&amp;nbsp;differentiable and functionally integrable with one another. The high levels of differentiation&amp;nbsp;and integration, in turn, enable the brain to produce the richest conscious experiences from the&amp;nbsp;smallest number of neurons and neuronal connections. Consequently, across individuals, those&amp;nbsp;with a smaller brain volume but a higher structural diversity tend to have richer conscious experiences than those with a larger brain volume but a lower structural diversity. Moreover, within&amp;nbsp;individuals, a reduction in neuronal connections, if accompanied by an increase in structural&amp;nbsp;diversity, will result in richer conscious experiences, and vice versa. These findings suggest&amp;nbsp;that having a larger number of neurons and neuronal connections is not necessarily beneficial&amp;nbsp;for consciousness; in contrast, an optimal brain architecture for consciousness is one where&amp;nbsp;the richest conscious experiences are generated from the smallest number of neurons and neuronal connections, at the minimal cost of biological material, physical space, and metabolic energy.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">MIND Group</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-10-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://philosophymindscience.org/index.php/phimisci/article/view/9185</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.33735/phimisci.2021.9185</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Philosophy and the Mind Sciences; Vol. 2 (2021): Philosophy and the Mind Sciences, 2021</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2699-0369</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.33735/phimisci.2021</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://philosophymindscience.org/index.php/phimisci/article/view/9185/8827</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2021 Chen Song</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>