<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>304</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">The Collateral Prisoner. A Bundist Holocaust Survivor between Nazi Perpetrators, Anti-Communism and British World Politics</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Wolff, Frank</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">While crossing the border in order to find his comrades in Belgium, Holocaust survivor and Bundist Herman Goldberg was arrested by the British military under the suspicion of being a Communist, a Trotskyist or even a militant member of the Zionist underground. After he had “proven” his “innocence,” he still remained incarcerated for months – to his torment together with high-ranked German Nazis. In a painfully composed letter, Goldberg turned to his comrades in New York who apparently were overwhelmed by the many problems risen by this unique source of post-Holocaust martyrdom of a political activist. Arguing that the collateral prisoner Goldberg suffered this deeply insulting treatment because he was not a member of the movements the British were afraid of, this article presents a full translation of this newly discovered document as well as a contextual interpretation.Bielefeld University / Johns Hopkins University</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2011-09-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://incs.ub.rub.de/index.php/INCS/article/view/304</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">The International Newsletter of Communist Studies; Vol. 17 No. 24 (2011); 78-91</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1862-698X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://incs.ub.rub.de/index.php/INCS/article/view/304/262</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2015 The International Newsletter of Communist Studies</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>