<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>315</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Presentations and Announcements</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Authors, Various</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">• Juliette Cadiot, Dominique Arel, Larissa Zakharova (eds.): Cacophonies d'empire. Le gouvernement des langues dans l'Empire russe et en Union soviétique, Paris, CNRS Editions, 2010. 368 p. ISBN 978-2-2710-7031-9 • Oleg Chlevnjuk: Chozjain. Stalin i utverždenie stalinskoj diktatury [Master of the House. Stalin and the Establishment of the Stalinist Dictatorship], Moskva, ROSSPEN, 2010. 478 p. (Istorija stalinizma). ISBN: 978-5-8243-1314-7• Romain Ducoulombier: Camarades. La Naissance du Parti Communiste en France. Préface de Marc Lazar, Paris, Perrin, 2010. 430 p. ISBN 978-2-2620-3416-0• Malte Griesse: Communiquer, juger et agir sous Staline. La personne prise entre ses liens avec les proches et son rapport au système politico-idéologique, Frankfurt am Main e.a., Lang, 2011. XII, 536 p. ISBN: 978-3-631-60446-5• Narihiko Ito, Annelies Laschitza, Ottokar Luban (eds.): Rosa Luxemburg. Ökonomische und historisch-politische Aspekte ihres Werkes. Internationale Rosa-Luxemburg-Gesellschaft in Tokio, April 2007, und Berlin, Januar 2009, Berlin, Dietz, 2010. 236 p. ISBN 978-3-3200-2233-4 • Gerd Koenen: Was war der Kommunismus?, Göttingen, Vandenhoeck &amp;amp; Ruprecht, 2010. 143 p. (FRIAS Rote Reihe. 2). ISBN 978-3-5253-2301-4 • Grigorij G. Kosač: Kommunisty Bližnego Vostoka v SSSR [Communists from the Middle East in the USSR]. 1920-1930-e gody, Moskva, RGGU, 2009. 268 p. ISBN 978-5-7281-1004-0 • Aleksandr Livšin: Nastroenija i političeskie ėmocii v Sovetskoj Rossii [Morale and Political Emotions in Soviet Russia]. 1917-1932 gg., Moskva, ROSSPEN, 2010. 344 p. (Istorija stalinizma). ISBN 978-5-8243-1358-1 • Alex Marshall: The Caucasus under Soviet Rule, London-New York, Routledge, 2010. VIII, 387 p. (Routledge Studies in the History of Russia and Eastern Europe). ISBN 978-0-415-41012-0 • Vladimir G. Mosolov: IMĖL. Citadel' partijnoj ortodoksii. Iz istorii Instituta marksizma-leninizma pri CK KPSS [IMEL. Fortress of Party Orthodoxy. The History of the Institute of Marxism-Leninism at the CC of the CPSU]. 1921-1956, Moskva, Novyj chronograf, 2010. 600 p. ISBN 978-5-94881-104-8 • Jürgen Mothes: Lateinamerika und der "Generalstab" der Weltrevolution. Zur Lateinamerika-Politik der Komintern. Herausgegeben von Klaus Meschkat, Berlin, Dietz, 2010. 304 p. (Geschichte des Kommunismus und des Linkssozialismus. 14). ISBN 978-3-3200-2235-8 • Matthias Neumann: The Communist Youth League and the Transformation of the Soviet Union. 1917-1932, London-New York, Routledge, 2011. XXI, 289 p. (BASEES/Routledge series on Russian and East European studies. 76). ISBN: 978-0-415-55957-7 • Serge Wolikow: L’Internationale Communiste. 1919-1943. Le Komintern ou le rêve déchu du parti mondial de la révolution, Paris, Les Editions de l’Atelier, 2010. 288 p. ISBN 978-2-7082-4131-2</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2011-09-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://incs.ub.rub.de/index.php/INCS/article/view/315</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">The International Newsletter of Communist Studies; Vol. 17 No. 24 (2011); 150-155</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1862-698X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://incs.ub.rub.de/index.php/INCS/article/view/315/273</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2015 The International Newsletter of Communist Studies</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>