<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>361</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Presentations and Announcements</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Authors, Various</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">• Vadim V. Damier: Anarcho-Syndicalism in the 20th Century. Translated from Russian by Malcolm Archibald, Edmonton, Black Cat Press, 2009. VI, 233 p. • Stefan Karner, Barbara Stelzl-Marx (eds.): Stalins letzte Opfer. Verschleppte und erschossene Österreicher in Moskau 1950-1953. Unter Mitartbeit von Daniela Almer, Wien-München, Böhlau, Oldenbourg, 2009. 676 p. (Kriegsfolgen-Forschung. 5).• Sobhanlal Datta Gupta (ed.): The Ryutin Platform. Stalin and the Crisis of Proletarian Dictatorship. Platform of the “Union of Marxists-Leninists”. Translated by Pranab Ghosh and Susmita Bhattacharya from the original Russian, Kolkata, Seribaan, 2010. 152 p. • Sonia Combe (ed.), in cooperation with Paul Gradvohl, Charles Kecskeméti, Antoine Marès and Jean-Charles Szurek: Archives et histoire dans les sociétés post-communistes, Paris, La Découverte, 2009. 332 p. (Collection Recherches). • Łukasz Kamiński, Krzysztof Persak, Jens Gieseke (eds.): Handbuch der kommunistischen Geheimdienste in Osteuropa 1944-1991, Göttingen, Vandenhoeck &amp;amp; Ruprecht, 2008. 420 p. (Wissenschaftliche Reihe der BStU. 33).• John Earl Haynes, Harvey Klehr, Alexander Vassiliev: Spies. The Rise and Fall of the KGB in America, New Haven, Yale University Press, 2009. LIII, 650 p. • Peter Huber, Ralph Hug (eds.): Die Schweizer Spanienfreiwilligen. Biografisches Handbuch, Zürich, Rotpunktverlag, 2009. 478 p.• Alexander Rabinowitch: Die Sowjetmacht. Das erste Jahr, Essen, Mehring Verlag, 2010.• Grigorij Grigorov: Povoroty sud'by i proizvol. Vospominanija. 1905-1927 gody, Moskva, OGI, 2005. 536 p. (Častnyj archiv); Grigorij Grigorov: Povoroty sud’by I proizvol. Vospominanija. 1927-1972, [Akko, Israel], s.p., [2008]. 682 p.• David Lee McMullen: Strike! The Radical Insurrections of Ellen Dawson. Foreword by Richard Greenwald and Timothy Minchin, Gainesville, University Press of Florida, 2010. 264 p.• Xavier Botterman: Histoire du mouvement communiste à Verviers. 1919-1940. Avantpropos de Milou Rikir, Bruxelles, CARCOB, 2009. 193 p. (Travaux historiques. 3). • Manuel Bueno Lluch, Sergio Gálvez Biesca (eds.): Nosotros los comunistas. Memoria, identidad e historia social, Madrid-Sevilla, Fundación de Investigaciones Marxistas, Atrapasueños, 2009. 457 p. (FIM historia).</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2010-07-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://incs.ub.rub.de/index.php/INCS/article/view/361</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">The International Newsletter of Communist Studies; Vol. 16 No. 23 (2010); 152-163</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1862-698X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://incs.ub.rub.de/index.php/INCS/article/view/361/319</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2015 The International Newsletter of Communist Studies</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>