<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>409</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Abrasivity of rock and soil</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Küpferle, J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Röttger, A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Theisen, W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Alber, M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Mechanized Tunneling</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">TBM</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Abrasivity of hard rock and soil</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">LCPC</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">LAC</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Cerchar</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">CAI</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">tool wear</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">wear-prediction</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">The abrasivity of rock and soil is a commonly determined property, which is used for the estimationof the wear of excavation tools. Therefore, different laboratory test have been developed over thelast decades. Within this work, the often used LCPC- and Cerchar-test are presented. Theinfluence of the steel sample material on the determined abrasivity is analyzed in terms of thetribological system, which describes the components and interactions influencing the wear of thetunneling tools. The problems and inaccuracies in terms of the test methods are discussed anddescribed from the view of materials technology. To determine a sufficient wear-prediction modelfor excavation tools, laboratory tests like LCPC and Cerchar are useful, but they have to beconsidered in the tribological context. This means that it is necessary to map as muchcharacteristics as possible from the associated tribological system. The different systemcomponents and their interactions have to be taken into account to determine a precise andsufficient wear-prediction model. The mandatory influence of the steel sample material on theresults of the presented test methods and thus on the abrasivity of rock and soil has been pointedout.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-11-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icscm.ub.rub.de/index.php/ICSCM/article/view/409</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.13154/icscm.3.2015.262-271</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">International Conference on Stone and Concrete Machining (ICSCM); Vol. 3 (2015); 262-271</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icscm.ub.rub.de/index.php/ICSCM/article/view/409/365</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2015 J. Küpferle, A. Röttger, W. Theisen, M. Alber</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>