<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>414</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Wear at elevated temperatures – microstructural investigations of tool materials after high temperature sliding wear</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Walter, M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Egels, G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Röttger, A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Theisen, W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">High temperature sliding wear</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">high temperature hardness</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">cemented carbides</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">high-speed steel</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">tribochemical wear layer</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">The presented study investigates the hardness and sliding wear behavior of cemented carbidesand high-speed tool steels at elevated temperatures. Therefore, experimental analysis focus on thebehavior and the microstructural changes of the aforementioned materials during sliding wear atroom temperature, 400°C, and 600°C. Investigations are performed with respect to materialsmechanical properties, which are represented by high temperature hardness measurements. As aresult a main output of this study is an overview about the interdependencies of the microstructureand the high temperature hardness of tool materials (cemented carbides, high-speed steels).Results show that the absolute value of the room temperature and the high temperature hardnessof cemented carbides are connected to the WC-carbide volume fraction. In contrast, thedevelopment of the hardness with increasing temperature is mainly influenced by the volumefraction and the characteristics of the binder matrix. In addition to the investigation of cementedcarbides, the hardness of HS 6-5-3 steel grade at elevated temperatures was investigated. Thevalue of the high temperature hardness of HS 6-5-3 high-speed steel is comparable to thehardness of cemented carbide materials, having higher binder content of 30 vol.-%.The absolutevalue and the temperature dependent course of the high temperature hardness of the high-speedsteel are further influenced by the applied heat-treatment. Moreover, detailed wear experimentsand microscopic analyses of the worn surfaces of selected materials are presented. Theseinvestigations show the main differences between room temperature sliding wear and hightemperature sliding wear. In the systems studied, an increase in testing temperature leads to arapid decrease of friction and wear rate. Microscopic investigations reveal that, the reason for thiseffect is the formation of a tribochemical wear layer at the surface of the wear bodies. This layersuppresses direct metallic contact and changes the characteristics of the tribological system.Discussed issues of high temperature sliding wear are the formation and stability of tribochemicalwear layers, their connection to and support by the bulk material as well as the fracturing anddamage of the layer-bulk-material compound.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-11-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icscm.ub.rub.de/index.php/ICSCM/article/view/414</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.13154/icscm.3.2015.320-334</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">International Conference on Stone and Concrete Machining (ICSCM); Vol. 3 (2015); 320-334</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icscm.ub.rub.de/index.php/ICSCM/article/view/414/370</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2015 M. Walter, G. Egels, A. Röttger, W. Theisen</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>