<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>9312</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Cryptanalysis of Efficient Masked Ciphers: Applications to Low Latency</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Beyne, Tim</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Dhooghe, Siemen</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Moradi, Amir</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Rezaei Shahmirzadi, Aein</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Hardware</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Linear Cryptanalysis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Masking</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Probing Security</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Side- Channel Analysis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Threshold Implementations</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">This work introduces second-order masked implementation of LED, Midori, Skinny, and Prince ciphers which do not require fresh masks to be updated at every clock cycle. The main idea lies on a combination of the constructions given by Shahmirzadi and Moradi at CHES 2021, and the theory presented by Beyne et al. at Asiacrypt 2020. The presented masked designs only use a minimal number of shares, i.e., three to achieve second-order security, and we make use of a trick to pair a couple of S-boxes to reduce their latency. The theoretical security analyses of our constructions are based on the linear-cryptanalytic properties of the underlying masked primitive as well as SILVER, the leakage verification tool presented at Asiacrypt 2020. To improve this cryptanalytic analysis, we use the noisy probing model which allows for the inclusion of noise in the framework of Beyne et al. We further provide FPGA-based experimental security analysis confirming second-order protection of our masked implementations.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-11-19</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://tches.iacr.org/index.php/TCHES/article/view/9312</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.46586/tches.v2022.i1.679-721</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">IACR Transactions on Cryptographic Hardware and Embedded Systems; Volume 2022, Issue 1; 679-721</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2569-2925</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://tches.iacr.org/index.php/TCHES/article/view/9312/8877</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2021 Tim Beyne, Siemen Dhooghe, Amir Moradi, Aein Rezaei Shahmirzadi</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>