<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>7351</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Migration: An account of women’s empowerment in contemporary Namibia</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Venditto, Bruno</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">This paper aims to shed light on the phenomenon of human mobility in contemporary Namibia, concentrating in particular on gender relations. Family member/s by making the decision to move can be considered agents who, despite the external structural constraints they face, and/or as a result of interaction with them, seek to achieve their goals and live by their values in such a way as to change their and/or the family’s life and conditions. The research was guided by the constructivist grounded theory approach allowing the emergence of a ‘theory of migration’, which provides a better platform to assess the gender transformation brought about by internal migration in Namibia, and thus contributes to the current debate on migration. Female migration is regarded here as a conscientising process, which empowers women, giving them the opportunity to tackle the gender power relations and challenge the existing structural institutional settings.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Otjivanda Presse.Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-12-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://namibian-studies.com/index.php/JNS/article/view/7351</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Journal of Namibian Studies : History Politics Culture; Vol. 24 (2018); 85-106</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-5523</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1863-5954</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://namibian-studies.com/index.php/JNS/article/view/7351/6521</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>