<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>9384</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="de-DE">Where the Film Has the (Visual) Word? On the Visuality and Materiality of Illustrated Film Magazines Exemplified by Neue Filmwelt (1947–1953)</dc:title>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Where the Film Has the (Visual) Word? On the Visuality and Materiality of Illustrated Film Magazines Exemplified by Neue Filmwelt (1947–1953)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Fröhlich, Vincent</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">film periodicals</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">movie magazine</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">intermediality</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">film poster</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">rotogravure</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">halftone</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">typography</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">film still</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">German film history</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Filmzeitschrift</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Kinozeitschrift</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Intermedialität</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Filmposter</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Rotationstiefdruck</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Halbton</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Typografie</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Filmstill</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Deutsche Filmgeschichte</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="de-DE">Bislang wurden illustrierte Filmzeitschriften vor allem als filmhistorische Quellen genutzt. Der folgende Beitrag rückt stattdessen ihre Visualität, Medialität und Materialität in den Vordergrund. Anhand des ostdeutschen Kinomagazins "Neue Filmwelt" widmet er sich der übergeordneten Frage: Welches Filmwissen und Verständnis des Films verhandeln illustrierte Filmzeitschriften in ihrer bisher weitgehend unbeachteten Visualität und in ihrer sinnlich-materiellen Präsenz? Der Essay schlägt vor, sich diesem intermedialen Verhältnis mit drei Fokussierungen anzunähern: Inwiefern schreibt sich die Zeitschrift in das Filmstill ein? Auf welche Art und Weise eignen sich diese Zeitschriften Bilder, Symbole, Signets und Typografien des Kinos an? Und in welcher Hinsicht positionieren sich illustrierte Kinomagazine damit in ihrer Beziehung zum Film als visuell, materiell und kulturell eigene Medienprodukte?</dc:description>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">To date, film magazines have primarily seen use as sources when researching individual periods of cinema history, rather than as objects of study themselves. Instead, the following paper brings the visuality, mediality and materiality of film periodicals to the fore. The question being addressed is the following: What kind of film knowledge and film understanding do illustrated film magazines negotiate in their presentation and selection—precisely in their (hitherto mainly disregarded) visuality, in their appearance, in their sensual material presence? The East German magazine Neue Filmwelt serves as an example for this approach. The essay proposes three ways of looking at the visual intermedial relation to film: How the magazine inscribes its words onto the picture; how it appropriates pictures, symbols, signets and typographies associated with cinema; and how it thereby outlines its very own position as a cultural and visual product in connection to film.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">DFG-Research Unit 2288 "Journalliteratur"</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-12-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ojs.ub.rub.de/index.php/PerIc/article/view/9384</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.46586/PerIc.2021.1.21-48</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">PeriodIcon; Vol. 1 No. 1 (2021): periodICON; 21-48</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2628-8354</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ojs.ub.rub.de/index.php/PerIc/article/view/9384/8961</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/legalcode</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>