<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>8620</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">WAGE: An Authenticated Encryption with a Twist</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>AlTawy, Riham</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Gong, Guang</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Mandal, Kalikinkar</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Rohit, Raghvendra</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Authenticated encryption</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Pseudorandom bit generators</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Welch-Gong permutation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Lightweight cryptography</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">This paper presents WAGE, a new lightweight sponge-based authenticated cipher whose underlying permutation is based on a 37-stage Galois NLFSR over F27. At its core, the round function of the permutation consists of the well-analyzed Welch-Gong permutation (WGP), primitive feedback polynomial, a newly designed 7-bit SB sbox and partial word-wise XORs. The construction of the permutation is carried out such that the design of individual components is highly coupled with cryptanalysis and hardware efficiency. As such, we analyze the security of WAGE against differential, linear, algebraic and meet/miss-in-the-middle attacks. For 128-bit authenticated encryption security, WAGE achieves a throughput of 535 Mbps with hardware area of 2540 GE in ASIC ST Micro 90 nm standard cell library. Additionally, WAGE is designed with a twist where its underlying permutation can be efficiently turned into a pseudorandom bit generator based on the WG transformation (WG-PRBG) whose output bits have theoretically proved randomness properties.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-06-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://tosc.iacr.org/index.php/ToSC/article/view/8620</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.13154/tosc.v2020.iS1.132-159</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">IACR Transactions on Symmetric Cryptology; Volume 2020, Special Issue 1 ; 132-159</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2519-173X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://tosc.iacr.org/index.php/ToSC/article/view/8620/8186</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2020 Riham AlTawy, Guang Gong, Kalikinkar Mandal, Raghvendra Rohit</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>