<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>8669</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Beyond-Birthday-Bound Secure Cryptographic Permutations from Ideal Ciphers with Long Keys</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Nakamichi, Ryota</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Iwata, Tetsu</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Cryptographic permutation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Ideal cipher</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Provable security</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Indifferentiability</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Coefficient-H technique</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Coron et al. showed a construction of a 3-round 2n-bit cryptographic permutation from three independent n-bit ideal ciphers with n-bit keys (TCC 2010). Guo and Lin showed a construction of a (2d − 1)-round dn-bit cryptographic permutation from 2d − 1 independent n-bit ideal ciphers with kn-bit keys, where d = k + 1 (Cryptography and Communications, 2015). These constructions have an indifferentiability security bound of O(q2/2n) against adversaries that make at most q queries. The bound is commonly referred to as birthday-bound security. In this paper, we show that a 5-round version of Coron et al.’s construction and (2d+1)-round version of Guo and Lin’s construction yield a cryptographic permutation with an indifferentiability security bound of O(q2/22n), i.e., by adding two more rounds, these constructions have beyond-birthday-bound security. Furthermore, under the assumption that q ≤ 2n, we show that Guo and Lin’s construction with 2d+2l−1 rounds yields a cryptographic permutation with a security bound of O(q2/2(l+1)n), where 1 ≤ l ≤ d − 1, i.e., the security bound exponentially improves by adding every two more rounds, up to 4d − 3 rounds. To the best of our knowledge, our result gives the first cryptographic permutation that is built from n-bit ideal ciphers and has a full n-bit indifferentiability security bound.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-07-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://tosc.iacr.org/index.php/ToSC/article/view/8669</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.13154/tosc.v2020.i2.68-92</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">IACR Transactions on Symmetric Cryptology; Volume 2020, Issue 2; 68-92</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2519-173X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://tosc.iacr.org/index.php/ToSC/article/view/8669/8227</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2020 Ryota Nakamichi, Tetsu Iwata</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>