<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>7263</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Presenting the Law: Text and Imagery on Dutch Ten Commandments Panels</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Wubs, Jacolien</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Ten Commandments panels</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Reformed visual culture</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">church interior</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Many Dutch Calvinist churches house a Ten Commandments panel, installed in the late sixteenth or seventeenth century as part of the Reformed adaptation of the medieval&amp;nbsp;Catholic church interior. In this article, the characteristic design of Ten Commandments panels&amp;nbsp;is analyzed as a form of Calvinist visual culture. It suggests that these panels were primarilymade to be viewed rather than thoroughly read. The remarkably figurative Moses imagery on&amp;nbsp;panels points at a divergence between the rigid Reformed theological image prohibition and&amp;nbsp;the practice of the adaptation of the church interior. The placement of Ten Commandments&amp;nbsp;panels in the Reformed church interior highlights their symbolic value: It signified the need&amp;nbsp;for self-examination of the participants in the Lord’s Supper. The original spatial setting of Ten Commandments panels also shows how the newly Reformed furnishing and use of church space&amp;nbsp;was rooted in its late medieval Catholic past.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-07-27</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/7263</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.13154/er.v7.2018.78-108</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Entangled Religions; Vol. 7 (2018): Between the Altar and the Pulpit: The (New?) Materiality of the Spiritual; 78-108</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2363-6696</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/7263/6441</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2018 Jacolien Wubs</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>