<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>7343</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Evangelicals and the Encounter with Islam: Changing Christian Identity in Multi-Faith Britain</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Smith, Greg</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">evangelicals</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">inter-faith</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Islam</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Christianity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Britain</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Over the last fifty years, British society has changed from a Christendom&amp;nbsp;model, where the default religious identity was Church of England, to a religiously diverse&amp;nbsp;society, where religious identity is a significant marker for minorities in the population. Among&amp;nbsp;Christians, strong religious belief and belonging is most likely to be expressed by those who&amp;nbsp;identify as evangelical. In many parts of the world, and especially in the USA, evangelical&amp;nbsp;discourse on the subject of non-Christian faiths, especially Islam, suggests profound antipathy&amp;nbsp;to ‘other’ beliefs and sometimes hostility to their adherents. In contrast, evidence presented in&amp;nbsp;this paper from a recent Evangelical Alliance panel survey suggests a range of nuanced viewsin the community of evangelical Christians in the UK. Although over 80% affirmed that Jesus is&amp;nbsp;the only way of salvation, and 84% thought Christianity is the only path to God, more extended&amp;nbsp;comments show that a wide range of views exist, from the paranoid or exclusive to a view&amp;nbsp;that is tolerant and broadly inclusive. The paper will examine the associations between these&amp;nbsp;views and various demographic and theological factors and seek to explain the data in terms&amp;nbsp;of the patterns of contemporary everyday inter-faith encounters, with specific emphasis on the&amp;nbsp;Abrahamic faiths, especially Islam. The situation is discussed in a framework of dynamics and&amp;nbsp;stability, where religious contact between faith communities has both crystallized beliefs and&amp;nbsp;identities and opened up new possibilities for alliances against the secular world.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-11-21</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/7343</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.13154/er.v5.2018.154-209</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Entangled Religions; Vol. 5 (2018); 154-209</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2363-6696</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/7343/6515</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2018 Greg Smith</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>