<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>7344</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Official Buddhism in Russia’s Politics and Education - Religion, Indigeneity, and Patriotism in Buryatia</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Sablin, Ivan</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Buddhism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Russia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Buryat</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">tradition</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">education</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">nationalism</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Focusing on organized Buddhism in the Republic of Buryatia and analyzing the&amp;nbsp;statements of Khambo Lama Damba Aiusheev of the Buddhist Traditional Sangha of Russia and&amp;nbsp;the textbooks used for teaching religion in public schools, the article discusses the different&amp;nbsp;aspects of the relations between religion and state as applied to Buddhism in contemporary&amp;nbsp;Russia in general and Buryatia in particular. The imperial politics of diversity management and&amp;nbsp;especially the legacies of confessional governance in the Russian Empire and the Soviet Union&amp;nbsp;made the four “traditional religions”—Orthodox Christianity, Islam, Buddhism, and Judaism—an important part of “federal” nation-building. Despite the overall desecularization of the&amp;nbsp;Russian state and the long history of relations between the state and organized Buddhism, the&amp;nbsp;predominantly Buryat, centralized organization Buddhist Traditional Sangha of Russia did not&amp;nbsp;assert its claim to represent all Russian Buddhists. State efforts to establish a system of four&amp;nbsp;“traditional religions,” providing inter alia a spiritual foundation for Russian patriotism, also did&amp;nbsp;not succeed. Buddhism remained decentralized in both administrative and semantic terms and&amp;nbsp;did not lose its connections to the communities outside Russia. In Buryatia itself, Shamanism&amp;nbsp;and Orthodox Christianity continuously challenged attempts to present Buddhism as the only&amp;nbsp;Buryat “traditional religion.”</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-11-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/7344</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.13154/er.v5.2018.210-249</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Entangled Religions; Vol. 5 (2018); 210-249</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2363-6696</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/7344/6516</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/7344/8279</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2018 Ivan Sablin</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>