<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>7367</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Acculturated Otherness. Christian Churches and Wedding Chapels in Modern Japanese Society</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Löffler, Beate</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Japan</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Christianity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">popular culture</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">church architecture</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">mission</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">wedding chapel</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">acculturation</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">During the latter half of the nineteenth century, the Japanese government&amp;nbsp;ended the centuries-long Japanese policy of isolation and initiated a rapid modernization&amp;nbsp;effort that aimed to create a competitive Japanese nation state. In addition to such changes&amp;nbsp;as new family law, compulsory education, and redistribution of property, the government&amp;nbsp;contracted foreign experts with the goal of importing western knowledge. As a result, civil&amp;nbsp;engineers, artists, and physicians started moving to Japan, as did missionaries. This resulted in&amp;nbsp;intense cultural encounter and negotiation, in the course of which Christian faith and Western&amp;nbsp;church architecture became acculturated in Japan. This article sketches the socio-cultural and&amp;nbsp;technological parameters shaping Japanese Christian church buildings from the 1860s onwards&amp;nbsp;as well as the transfer of meanings and forms from an explicitly Western tradition into a&amp;nbsp;Western-looking and yet entirely Japanese tradition of Christianity. It sketches a second line&amp;nbsp;of transfer as well, that reinterpreted the ‘church’ as an architectural form into the Wedding-Chapel-Romanticism of the non-Christian Japanese mainstream wedding industry.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-12-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/7367</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.13154/er.v5.2018.312-346</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Entangled Religions; Vol. 5 (2018); 312-346</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2363-6696</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/7367/6537</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2018 Beate Löffler</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>