<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>7395</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Islam and Buddhism: The Arabian Prequel?</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Akasoy, Anna</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Islam</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Buddhism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">tradition</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Conventionally, the first Muslim-Buddhist encounters are thought to have taken place in&amp;nbsp;the context of the Arab-Muslim expansions into eastern Iran in the mid-seventh century, the conquest&amp;nbsp;of Sind in 711 and the rise of the Islamic empire. However, several theories promoted in academic and&amp;nbsp;popular circles claim that Buddhists or other Indians were present in western Arabia at the eve of Islam&amp;nbsp;and thus shaped the religious environment in which Muhammad’s movement emerged. This article&amp;nbsp;offers a critical survey of the most prominent arguments adduced to support this view and discusses&amp;nbsp;the underlying attitudes to the Islamic tradition, understood as a body of ideas and practices, and&amp;nbsp;Islamic Tradition, understood as a body of texts. Such theories appear to be radical challenges of the&amp;nbsp;Islamic tradition insofar as they seek to reinscribe the presence of religious communities in conventional&amp;nbsp;narratives of Islamic origins that do not acknowledge them. On the other hand, they often operate&amp;nbsp;with an unreconstructed reliance upon the sources of the Islamic Tradition. The assessment focuses ondescriptions of the Ka’ba and objects associated with it as well as on a story about an Indian physician who&amp;nbsp;diagnosed an illness of Muhammad’s wife Aisha. While Indian or Buddhist connections with western Arabia&amp;nbsp;and early Islam do not appear to be entirely impossible, the evidence does not amount to a persuasive&amp;nbsp;case for the early seventh century.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-03-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/7395</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.13154/er.v8.2019.1-32</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Entangled Religions; Vol. 8 (2019); 1-32</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2363-6696</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/7395/6567</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/7395/8254</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2019 Anna Akasoy</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>