<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>8283</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Where Do the Multi-Religious Origins of Islam Lie? A Topological Approach to a Wicked Problem</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Sing, Manfred</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">inter-religious contact</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">production of space</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">emergence of Islam</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Genesis of the Qurʾān</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Mecca and Medina</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">The revelation of Islam in Arabic, its emergence in the Western Arabian Peninsula, and its&amp;nbsp;acquaintance with Biblical literature seem to be clear indications for Islam’s birthplace and its religious&amp;nbsp;foundations. While the majority of academic scholarship accepts the historicity of the revelation in Mecca&amp;nbsp;and Medina, revisionist scholars have started questioning the location of early Islam with increasing&amp;nbsp;fervour in recent years. Drawing on the isolation of Mecca and the lack of clear references to Mecca&amp;nbsp;in ancient and non-Muslim literature before the mid-eighth century, these scholars have cast doubt on&amp;nbsp;the claim that Mecca was already a trading outpost and a pilgrimage site prior to Islam, questioning the&amp;nbsp;traditional Islamic and Orientalist view. Space, thus, plays a prominent role in the debate on the origins&amp;nbsp;of Islam, although space is almost never conceptually discussed. In the following paper, I challenge the&amp;nbsp;limited understanding of space in revisionist as well as mainstream scholarship. For the most part, this&amp;nbsp;scholarship is not really interested in the multi-religious landscape sui generis, but understands early&amp;nbsp;Islam either as a stable or an unstable entity that either reworked or digested the impact of Judaism&amp;nbsp;and Christianity. In contrast, my contention is based on the view that Islam emerged neither “in” Mecca&amp;nbsp;nor anywhere else, but that Muslims’ practical and symbolic actions produced such places as Mecca,&amp;nbsp;Medina, and the Ḥijāz as the central places of Islam. My argument is threefold: Firstly, the production&amp;nbsp;of the Meccan space and its central meaning for Islam were mutually dependant, gradual processes.&amp;nbsp;Secondly, the creation of an exclusively Muslim space in the Ḥijāz conversely inscribed multi-religiosity&amp;nbsp;into the general topology of early Islam. Thirdly, the early history of Islam hints at practices of un/doing differences, exemplified by instances of sharing, the creation of ambivalence, and processes ofpurification. Moreover, my contribution questions the way in which research on the origins of Islam has&amp;nbsp;become a meaningful object of knowledge about the “true” nature of Islam against the background of&amp;nbsp;populist discourses on Islam.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-04-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/8283</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.13154/er.v9.2019.165-210</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Entangled Religions; Vol. 9 (2019): The Changing Landscapes of Cross-Faith Places and Practices; 165-210</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2363-6696</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/8283/7634</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/8283/8283</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2019 Manfred Sing</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>