<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>8284</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Towards a Multi-Religious Topology of Islam: The Global Circulation of a Mutable Mobile</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Sing, Manfred</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Religious diversity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Islam</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Judaism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Christianity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">inter-religious entanglement</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">religious tolerance</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">space</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Middle East</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Europe</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Africa</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">America</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Asia</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Narratives of the origins, the history, and the present state of Islam always entail spatial&amp;nbsp;claims. Accordingly, Islam emerged in the Arabian Peninsula, spread over its so-called heartlands, and&amp;nbsp;became a world religion. A common understanding inscribes Islam onto the Orient and opposes it to&amp;nbsp;Europe, the Occident, or the West. Such spatial claims are faced with fundamental challenges and&amp;nbsp;epistemological shortcomings because neither Islam nor space are naturally given, bounded entities.&amp;nbsp;Rather, different historical actors and observers produce spatialized Islam. In this chapter, I challenge&amp;nbsp;the notion that “Muslim space” is a useful analytical concept, and scrutinize the ways in which&amp;nbsp;academic discourses inscribe Islam onto space and history. As an alternative, I propose a topology that&amp;nbsp;understands the production of space as a multi-dimensional social process, including Muslim and non-Muslim perspectives at the same time. Thus, I delineate the topology of Islam as variegated, dynamic,&amp;nbsp;and multi-religious from its inception. My argument is that Islam’s trans-regional spread turned it into a&amp;nbsp;polycentric, mutable mobile characterized by internal and external diversity. I further argue that images&amp;nbsp;of Islam are an integral, yet often concealed part of European and Western knowledge production and&amp;nbsp;self-understanding. Epistemologically, this perspective argues that the “Islamization of Islam” is nowhere&amp;nbsp;better visible than in the spatial ramifications of discourses that marginalize, exclude, or obfuscate both&amp;nbsp;the multi-religious experiences in Islamic contexts and the continuous presence of Islam in European&amp;nbsp;history.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-04-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/8284</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.13154/er.v9.2019.211-272</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Entangled Religions; Vol. 9 (2019): The Changing Landscapes of Cross-Faith Places and Practices; 211-272</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2363-6696</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/8284/7635</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/8284/8282</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2019 Manfred Sing</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>