<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>8323</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Memory and Alterity in Zar: Religious Contact and Change in the Sudan</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Kenyon, Susan M</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Zar spirit possession</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Sudan</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">military history</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">slavery</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">memory</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Drawing on long-term ethnographic research in the Blue Nile town of Sennar,&amp;nbsp;supported by archival and historical documentation, this article explores the history of Zar&amp;nbsp;spirit possession in Sudan, and the light this throws on the interplay of religions over the&amp;nbsp;past 150 years. Life history data supports the argument that contemporary Zar is grounded&amp;nbsp;in forms and rituals derived from the ranks of the ninteenth-century Ottoman army, and&amp;nbsp;these remain the basis of ritual events, even as they accommodate ongoing changes in&amp;nbsp;this part of Africa. Many of these changes are linked to the dynamic interplay of Zar with&amp;nbsp;forms of Islam, on the one hand, and Christianity, on the other. In the former colonial&amp;nbsp;periods, political power resided with the British, and Khawaja (European) Christian Zar&amp;nbsp;spirits are remembered as far more important. Today that authority in Zar has shifted to&amp;nbsp;spirits of foreign Muslims and local holy men, on the one hand, and to subaltern Blacks,&amp;nbsp;on the other. These speak to concerns of new generations of adepts even as changes in the&amp;nbsp;larger political and religious landscapes continue to transform the context of Zar.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-06-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/8323</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.13154/er.8.2019.8323</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Entangled Religions; Vol. 8 (2019)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2363-6696</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/8323/7672</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/8323/7673</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2019 Susan M Kenyon</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>