<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>8556</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">'Religion' in Late Antique Zoroastrianism and Manichaeism: Developing a Term in Counterpoint</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Rezania, Kianoosh</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">generic concept of religion</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Manichaeism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Zoroastrianism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Sasanian period</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">early Islamic period</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">daēnā/dēn</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">This article evaluates the development of a generic term for ‘religion’ in late antique Manichaeism and Zoroastrianism. It examines linguistic indications of the use of dēn/δēn as a generic term in the Manichaean Middle Iranian corpora, i.e. Middle Persian, Parthian, and Sogdian, as well as in the corpus of Zoroastrian Middle Persian. The paper considers declination in the plural, the attribution of universal quantifiers or demonstrative adjectives, comparison, and selection, as they occur in the above corpora, to be indicators of generic concepts. Acknowledging that third-century Manichaeism shaped the term for ‘religion’ in the Persian Empire, the paper scrutinizes the reflections of this formative process in Sasanian and also early Islamic Zoroastrianism. The resulting analysis of the linguistic evidence indicates that the newly coined Manichaean concept of ‘religion’ did not find considerable echoes in late antique Zoroastrianism. Furthermore, an investigation of the term daēnā- in the Avestan sources provides earlier evidence for the formation of the term ‘religion’ in pre-Sasanian Zoroastrianism. Finally, the paper highlights the significance of religious contact for the formation of a generic concept of religion.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-04-21</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/8556</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.13154/er.11.2020.8556</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Entangled Religions; Vol. 11 No. 2: Formative Exchanges between the Sasanid Empire and Late Antique Rome: Zoroastrianism, Manichaeism and Christianity in Contact</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2363-6696</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/8556/8124</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/8556/8125</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2020 Kianoosh Rezania</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>