<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>8573</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">From Manichaeism to Zoroastrianism: On the History of the Teaching of the ‘Two Principles’</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>König, Götz</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Zoroastrianism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Manichaeism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">dialectical development of dualism</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">The essential feature in the religious history of Pre-Islamic Iran is its dualistic worldview.&amp;nbsp; It marks all stages of Zoroastrianism and also Manichaeism, in which dualism can be regarded as the most important Zoroastrian piece of inheritance. The following essay concentrates on two aspects of this ‘inheritance’ that have been&amp;nbsp; overlooked until today: 1) The Manichaean dualism is consistently built on elements and tendencies that already existed, albeit covertly, in the Younger Avesta; and 2) The Manichaean dualism has thereby confronted Zoroastrian theologians with the task of giving an alternative and consistent formulation of dualism. Thus, the continuous attention both Dēnkard III and the Škand Gumānīg ī Wizār, two of the most philosophically inclined works in Pahlavi, give the concept of dualism seeks to articulate a relation between the notion of evil and the idea of the “finite,” and also to formulate the notion of "principle," seen as a demarcation from the Manichaean solution.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-07-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/8573</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.13154/er.11.2020.8573</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Entangled Religions; Vol. 11 No. 2: Formative Exchanges between the Sasanid Empire and Late Antique Rome: Zoroastrianism, Manichaeism and Christianity in Contact</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2363-6696</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/8573/8230</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/8573/8231</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2020 Götz König</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>