<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>8693</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Comparing Comparisons in Muslim Polemical Writings from Christian Iberia and Exile: Muḥammad al-Qaysī’s Kitāb Miftāḥ al-Dīn and the Anonymous Tratado de los dos caminos</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Colominas Aparicio, Mònica</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Polemical Comparisons</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Muslims in Christian Iberia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Moriscos</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Exile</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Tunisia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Kitāb Miftāḥ al-Dīn</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Tratado de los dos caminos</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Comparison figures prominently in the polemics of the Muslim, Christian, and Jewish inhabitants of the Iberian Peninsula in premodern and early modern times. Its pervasiveness as a figure of thought in their sources raises the question of variety in regard to comparison—that is, the multiple expressions of comparison as well as its numerous uses—particularly in the field of polemics. This paper discusses the functions of comparison in polemics as a necessary first step to advance current knowledge of comparison as a historical practice in the making of one’s identity and the definition of groups and individuals. The discussion will focus on writings by Muslims who lived in Christian Iberia. It will focus particularly on two anti-Christian polemics: that by the Tunisian author Muḥammad al-Qaysī in an as-yet unstudied Aljamiado copy (Spanish in Arabic characters); and the Tratado de los dos caminos (Treatise of the Two Roads), an early-seventeenth-century work of Islamic doctrine by the so-called “Refugee in Tunisia”. The analysis of these two works will address the most important common points and differences between their respective polemical comparisons.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-10-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/8693</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.46586/er.11.2020.8693</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Entangled Religions; Vol. 11 No. 4: Behaving Like Heathens. Polemical Comparisons and Pre-Modern Discourses of Religious Diversity from an Interdisciplinary Perspective</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2363-6696</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/8693/8302</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/8693/8303</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2020 Mònica Colominas Aparicio</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>