<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>8919</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">(PREPRINT) ‘Popular Ijtihad’ and Entangled Islamic Discourse on the Covid-19 Pandemic in Russia</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Islam in Russia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">coronavirus pandemic</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">sociology of Islam</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">religious authority</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">ijtihad</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">
In this article, I examine initial reactions of the Russian Muslim community in social networks to the spread of the coronavirus. My two main questions are: who and how reinterprets the category of Islamic piety in the context of the pandemic, and to what extent the online environment transforms the Islamic tradition. To answer them, I focus on the following key narratives of Russian Muslims’ online discourse on the pandemic: Covid-19 as a retaliation against China for the persecutions of Muslim Uighurs in Xinjiang region, the search for signs of the coming doomsday, as well as various approaches to the reinterpretation of religious piety. Moreover, I consider how the pandemic speeded up building the entangled glocalised discourse. In the context of increased role of transnational online Muslim community, I suggest the term ‘popular ijtihad’ to describe individualized forms of religious engagement that the crisis situation stimulated.The first review of this article can be found under the following link: (Review A) "‘Popular Ijtihad’ and Entangled Islamic Discourse on the Covid-19 Pandemic in Russia" | Entangled Religions (rub.de)The second review of this article can be found under the following link: (Review B) ‘Popular Ijtihad’ and Entangled Islamic Discourse on the Covid-19 Pandemic in Russia | Entangled Religions (rub.de)
</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-10-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/8919</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Entangled Religions; Vol. 12 No. 3: Religion and Pandemic: Shifts in Interpretations, Popular Lore, and Practices</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2363-6696</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/8919/8817</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/8919/8818</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2021 Anonymous</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>