<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>9179</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">(PREPRINT) Jain Life Reimagined: An Examination of Jain Practice and Discourse during the Covid-19 Pandemic</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Maes, Claire</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Jainism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">scholarly religious activities</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">environmentalism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">scientization</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">COVID-19 pandemic</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">universalization</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">
This article analyzes the effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on the religious practices and the public discourse of Jains in the U.S.A. and India. On the institutional level, I show how Jain organizations made extensive efforts to connect digitally with their community members when collective, in-person celebrations and temple visits were either reduced in number, limited in capacity, or cancelled because of the pandemic. Given the new importance of Jain online platforms, I address their potential role in both blurring sectarian boundaries and creating authentic sacred spaces. On the individual level, I examine the effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on the everyday religious practices of Jains. I conducted eight semi-structured interviews over Zoom between November 2020 and January 2021. I argue that while there is a great diversity of individual Jain responses, a common feature appears to be a significant increase of Jains participating in scholarly religious activities. In terms of the ways in which Jains talk, write, and reflect on the COVID-19 pandemic, I theorize that the Jain discourse on the COVID-19 pandemic is characterized by environmental concerns and by the processes of scientization and universalization. Building on the work of Knut Aukland (2016) that examines the role of science in contemporary Jain discussions, I define scientization as the ongoing process where Jains underline the convergence of their religion with modern science. With the term universalization, I refer to the noticeable trend among Jains to argue for the need to teach Jainism beyond the Jain community by showing its contemporary relevance and applicability to overcome global problems, such as the COVID-19 pandemic.
The first review is now online and can be found under the following link: (Review A) "Jain Life Reimagined: An Examination of Jain Practice and Discourse during the Covid-19 Pandemic" | Entangled Religions (rub.de)
</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-10-15</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en-US">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/9179</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Entangled Religions; Vol. 12 No. 3: Religion and Pandemic: Shifts in Interpretations, Popular Lore, and Practices</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2363-6696</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/9179/8789</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/article/view/9179/8790</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2021 Maes Claire</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>