<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>8771</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="de-DE">Literarisches Lernen im Spiegel internationaler Forschung</dc:title>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">German-language studies in literature education in the light of international research</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Winkler, Iris</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">German-language research in literature education</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">English-language research in literature education</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">classroom discussion</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">reader-oriented approaches to literature</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">text-oriented approaches to literature</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Literaturdidaktik</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">literarisches Gespräch</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Leserorientierung</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">Textorientierung</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="de-DE">englischsprachige literaturdidaktische Forschung</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="de-DE">Der vorliegende Beitrag stellt die These auf, dass die deutschsprachige Literaturdidaktik von einer stärkeren Berücksichtigung internationaler Forschung in mehrfacher Hinsicht profitieren kann. Dabei geht er von zwei in der deutschsprachigen Literaturdidaktik weithin akzeptierten Grundannahmen zum literarischen Lernen aus: erstens der Annahme, dass dem Wechselspiel von leser- und textorientierten Zugängen eine besondere Bedeutung beikommt, und zweitens der Annahme, dass das literarische Gespräch bei Einhaltung vorwiegend normativ gesetzter Kriterien eine zentrale Lehr- und Lernform ist. Zur Untersetzung dieser These wird der aktuelle deutschdidaktische Forschungsstand in Relation zu englischsprachigen internationalen literaturdidaktischen Forschungen gesetzt, die die ausgewählten Grundannahmen tangieren. Aus der gewählten Perspektive werden im deutschsprachigen Diskurs vorherrschende Annahmen und Befunde teils bestätigt, teils erweitert, teils in ein neues Licht gerückt.</dc:description>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">This paper argues that German-language research in literature education can benefit in several ways from a stronger consideration of international research. To illustrate this point, the paper examines two basic assumptions on literature education that are widely accepted in German-language research: First, it is assumed that the interplay of reader- and text-oriented approaches to literature is particularly important. Second, it is assumed that classroom discussions are a proper way of dealing with literary texts, as long as some normative prerequisites are concerned. With respect to these assumptions, the current state of German-language research on literature education is related to international (English-language) research. As a result, prevailing assumptions and findings in the German-language discourse are partly confirmed, partly extended, and partly seen in a new light.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="de-DE">Universitätsbibliothek der Ruhr-Universität Bochum</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-02-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ojs.ub.rub.de/index.php/SLLD/article/view/8771</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.46586/SLLD.Z.2021.8771</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="de-DE">Zeitschrift für Sprachlich-Literarisches Lernen und Deutschdidaktik; Bd. 1 (2021)</dc:source>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Journal for Language and Literature Learning and Didactics of German; Vol. 1 (2021)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2701-0589</dc:source>
	<dc:language>deu</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ojs.ub.rub.de/index.php/SLLD/article/view/8771/8379</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="de-DE">Copyright (c) 2021 Iris Winkler</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="de-DE">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>