<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>7431</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Governance, Politics, and Environmentalism in the Age of Mass Recreation: The Campaign Against ‘Village Lake Louise’</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Ingram, Darcy</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator>Smart, Sarah</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">social movements</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">postmaterialism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Canada</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Banff National Park</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Lake Louise</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">tourism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Canadian Parks and Wilderness Society (CPAWS)</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">National and Provincial Parks Association of Canada (NPPAC)</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">This article examines the successful environmental campaign against a massive ski resort development proposal known as ‘Village Lake Louise’ that was to be established in the 1970s in Banff National Park, Canada. Using postmaterialism and governance as conceptual lenses, the article presents this campaign as an early example of an environmental conflict that did not centre on primary resource extraction industries, for example forestry, mining, or hydroelectric development. At issue in this case was a growing recreation-based economy that drew on and reflected many of the same postmaterial values and perspectives that informed the environmentalists opposed to the project. In the process, the article demonstrates how the campaign against Village Lake Louise contributed to the institutionalisation of Canada’s environmental movement and to the development of a complex framework for environmental governance in that nation.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Klartext Verlag</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-05-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://moving-the-social.ub.rub.de/index.php/MTS/article/view/7431</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.13154/mts.59.2018.129-154</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Moving the Social; Vol. 59 (2018): Sex Workers’ Fights — Prostitutes’ Rights Movements in European and American Countries; 129-154</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-0394</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-0386</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://moving-the-social.ub.rub.de/index.php/MTS/article/view/7431/6603</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2018 Moving the Social</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>