<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>7500</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">What’s New in the History of Social Movements?</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Berger, Stefan</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">Jürgen Schmidt, August Bebel: Kaiser der Arbeiter, Zurich: Rotpunkt, 2013, ISBN 9783858695383, pp. 285.
Axel Weipert, Das Rote Berlin. Eine Geschichte der Berliner Arbeiterbewegung 1830–1934, Berlin: Berliner Wissenschafts-Verlag, 2013, ISBN 9783830532422, pp. 251.
Matthew Johnson, Militarism and the British Left, 1902–1914, Basingstoke: Palgrave Mac-Millan, 2013, ISBN 9781137274120, pp. xi+247.
Christopher Read, War and Revolution in Russia, 1914–1922: the Collapse of Tsarism and the Establishment of Soviet Power, Basingstoke: Palgrave MacMillan, 2013, ISBN 9780230239869, xiv+247.
Domink Rigoll, Staatsschutz in Westdeutschland. Von der Entnazifizierung zur Extremistenabwehr, Göttingen: Wallstein, 2013, ISBN 9783835310766, pp. 524.
Arne Hordt, Von Scargill zu Blair? Der britische Bergarbeiterstreik 1984–85 als Problem einer europäischen Zeitgeschichtsschreibung, Frankfurt am Main: Peter Lang, 2013, ISBN 9783631625118, pp. 124.
Andrea Hajek, Negotiating Memories of Protest in Western Europe. The Case of Italy, Basingstoke: Palgrave MacMillan, 2013, ISBN 9781137263773, pp. xi+220.
Cristina Flesher Fominaya and Laurence Cox (eds.), Understanding European Movements: New Social Movements, Global Justice Struggles, Anti-Austerity Protest, London: Routledge, 2013, ISBN 9780415638791, pp. xix+263.
Colin Barker, Laurence Cox, John Krinsky and Alf Gunvald Nilsen (eds.), Marxism and Social Movements, Leiden: Brill, 2013, ISBN 9789004211759, pp. vii+473.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Klartext Verlag</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-02</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://moving-the-social.ub.rub.de/index.php/MTS/article/view/7500</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.13154/mts.51.2014.313-334</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Moving the Social; Vol. 51 (2014): Lifes on the Left; 313-334</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-0394</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-0386</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://moving-the-social.ub.rub.de/index.php/MTS/article/view/7500/6672</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2015 Moving the Social - Journal of Social History and the History of Social Movements</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>