<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>7756</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Gerd Muhr und Maria Weber: Eine sozialpolitische Elite des DGB in den frühen Jahren der sozialliberalen Koalition (1969–1974)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Remeke, Stefan</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Deutscher Gewerkschaftsbund (DGB)</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Gewerkschaftsbewegung</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">1969-1974</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Gerd Muhr</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Maria Weber</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Confederation of German Trade Unions</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Trade Unions Movement</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">In this article Stefan Remeke analyses the sociopolitical elite of the ‘Federation of German Trade Unions’ (Deutscher Gewerkschaftsbund/DGB) in the time of reforms of the socioliberal coalition, considering Gerd Muhr and Maria Weber as examples. From 1969 to 1990 Muhr was deputy chairman of the DGB as well as Weber. She, as head of the christian-social movement in the DGB was member of the board from 1972 to 1982. Both decided about crucial key positions in the social policy of the German trade unions over a long period of time. Borsdorf ’s category of the “Gewerkschaftsmanager” will be applied on Muhr (SPD, member in the sociopolitical commission of the SPD) and Weber (CDU/CDA, chairperson of the CDA). The two acted as intermediaries between trade unions and parties (“Manager der politischen Beeinflussung”) and between the DGB and its particular members (“Manager der einheitsgewerkschaftlichen Partikularinteressen”). This interrelation will be presented in a comparative, biographical way.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Klartext Verlag</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-01-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://moving-the-social.ub.rub.de/index.php/MTS/article/view/7756</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.13154/mts.35.2006.207-223</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Moving the Social; Vol. 35 (2006): Die Gewerkschaftselite der Nachkriegszeit: Prägung - Funktion - Leitbilder; 207-223</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-0394</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-0386</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://moving-the-social.ub.rub.de/index.php/MTS/article/view/7756/6928</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2015 Moving the Social - Journal of Social History and the History of Social Movements</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>