<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>8387</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">What’s New in the History of Social Movements:: a Review Article</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Berger, Stefan</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">
Craig Browne: Critical Social Theory, London: Sage, 2017, 216 pp., ISBN: 978-1- 44624-693-1 (pbk).
Timothy J. LeCain: The Matter of History: How Things Create the Past, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2017, 366 pp., ISBN: 978-1-31646-025-2.
Constance Bantman and Bert Altena (eds.): Reassessing the Transnational Turn: Scales of Analysis in Anarchist and Syndicalist Studies, Oakland, CA: PM Press, 2017, 256 pp., ISBN: 978-1-62963-391-6.
Kevin Morgan: International Communism and the Cult of the Individual: Leaders, Tribunes and Martyrs under Lenin and Stalin, Basingstoke: Palgrave MacMillan, 2017, 363 pp., ISBN: 978-1-137-55667-7.
Konstantin Vössing: How Leaders Mobilize Workers: Social Democracy, Revolution, and Moderate Syndicalism, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2017, 320 pp., ISBN: 978-1-107-16517-5.
Marcelo Badaró Mattos: Laborers and Enslaved Workers: Experiences in Common in the Making of Rio de Janeiro’s Working Class, 1850–1920, Oxford: Berghahn Books, 2017, 186 pp., ISBN: 978-1-78533-629-4.
Markus Lundström: The Making of Resistance: Brazil’s Landless Movement and Narrative Enactment, Cham: Springer, 2017, 143 pp., ISBN: 978-3-319-55347-4. Priska Daphi: Becoming a Movement: Identity, Narrative and Memory in the European Global Justice Movement, London: Rowman &amp;amp; Littlefield, 2017, 164 pp., ISBN: 978-1-78660-380-7 (pbk).
Ekaterina Tarasova: Anti-Nuclear Movements in Discursive and Political Contexts: Between Expert Voices and Local Protests, Stockholm: Södertörn University, 2017, 305 pp., ISBN: 978-91-87843-81-5.
You Jae Lee: Koloniale Zivilgemeinschaft: Alltag und Lebensweise der Christen in Korea (1894 –1954), Frankfurt/Main: Campus, 2017, 323 pp., ISBN: 978-3-593- 50672-2.
Amerigo Caruso: Nationalstaat als Telos? Der konservative Diskurs in Preussen und Sardinien-Piemont 1840 –1870, Berlin: De Gruyter, 2017, 516 pp., ISBN: 978-3-11- 054207-3.
Uwe Fuhrmann: Die Entstehung der „Sozialen Marktwirtschaft“ 1948/49: Eine historische Dispositivanalyse, Konstanz: UVK, 2017, 359 pp., ISBN: 978-3-86764-665-9.
</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Klartext Verlag</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-10-15</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://moving-the-social.ub.rub.de/index.php/MTS/article/view/8387</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.13154/mts.62.2019.73-92</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Moving the Social; Vol. 62 (2019): Essays on Social History and the History of Social Movements; 73-92</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-0394</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-0386</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://moving-the-social.ub.rub.de/index.php/MTS/article/view/8387/7732</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>