<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>9050</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Gender, Populism and Anti-Immigrations: Ethno-Sexist, Femonationalist and Femoglobal Alliance</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Roth, Julia</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">right-wing populism and gender</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">anti-migration</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">ethno-sexism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">antifeminism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">sexual exceptionalism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">reverse anti-colonialism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Donald Trump</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Jair Bolsonaro</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">U.S.A.</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Brazil</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">AfD</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">


In current struggles over cultural hegemony, conservative and right-wing populist dis- course is marked by an omni-presence of topics related to gender and sexuality. This article examines the ways in which diverse actors of what will be called the ‘right-wing populist complex’ use gender in order to catapult a variety of arguments into the public sphere with particular focus on actors in the Americas and Germany. Suggest- ing a first set of Right-Wing Populist Patterns of Gendering1, the article pursues the question how seemingly emancipatory arguments function in right-wing discourse, especially in performing a modernisation paradigm, while simultaneously, and in of- ten paradoxical ways, promoting a program of re-traditionalisation. Therefore, often, gender arguments—like the sexual freedom of ‘autochtonous’ women—are used to justify anti-immigration and racist politics. One’s own society can thus be depicted as supposedly already fully emancipated in contrast to the alleged ‘backward’ social order of immigrants. Through this ethno-sexist twist, the article argues that gender provides right-wing populist discourse a useful tool for affectively bridging seemingly paradoxical arguments and transferring diverse social hierarchies shaped by late neo- liberalism onto the gender hierarchy of a society. Since gender as a discursive element is foundational for right-wing discourse, an analytical, systematic and intersectional gender lens—or a critical gender theory—is crucial in right-wing populism research in order to grasp patterns of gendering and their entanglements with racialisation and racist structures.


</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Klartext Verlag</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-08-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://moving-the-social.ub.rub.de/index.php/MTS/article/view/9050</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.46586/mts.65.2021.61-79</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Moving the Social; Vol. 65 (2021): Right-Wing Populist Movements and Gender; 61-79</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-0394</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-0386</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://moving-the-social.ub.rub.de/index.php/MTS/article/view/9050/8636</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2021 Moving the Social</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>