<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><id>9408</id>
	<dc:title xml:lang="en-US">Taking Nativism to the Streets: Historical Perspectives on Right-Wing Extremist Protest Campaigns against Immigration in Germany</dc:title>
	<dc:creator>Botsch, Gideon</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">antisemitism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">racism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">nativism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">radical right parties</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">radical right movements</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">protest</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">violence</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">terrorism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">Germany</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">nineteenth century</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en-US">twentieth century</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en-US">In this article, I give an overview on nativist street protests in Germany from the early&amp;nbsp;nineteenth century to the present from an historical perspective. In a preliminary remark,&amp;nbsp;I will reflect on some recent developments in Germany, where nativist protest&amp;nbsp;campaigns against immigration took place in the streets when voters were turning&amp;nbsp;towards the populist radical right party Alternative für Deutschland (AfD). In the first&amp;nbsp;section, I will outline an older tradition of anti-immigration protest in nineteenth and&amp;nbsp;early twentieth century Germany, which is closely connected to modern antisemitism.&amp;nbsp;In sections two and three, I will retrace how, from the late 1960s onward, the far&amp;nbsp;right in the Federal Republic of Germany (FRG) discovered concerns about immigration&amp;nbsp;in the German population, addressed them in protest campaigns and developed&amp;nbsp;narratives to integrate such sentiments into a broader right-wing extremist ideology,&amp;nbsp;itself deeply rooted in antisemitism. Studying nativism and the radical right from an&amp;nbsp;actor-oriented perspective, I will focus on traditionalist movements, including the&amp;nbsp;Nationaldemokratische Partei Deutschlands (NPD) and neo-Nazi groups.&amp;nbsp;</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en-US">Klartext Verlag</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-10-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://moving-the-social.ub.rub.de/index.php/MTS/article/view/9408</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.46586/mts.66.2021.43-62</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en-US">Moving the Social; Vol. 66 (2021): Unwelcome Participation: Ostracizing Public Protest in the Second Half of the Twentieth Century; 43-62</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-0394</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2197-0386</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://moving-the-social.ub.rub.de/index.php/MTS/article/view/9408/8952</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en-US">Copyright (c) 2021 Moving the Social</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>